Victor Shcherbakov

Software Developer with 13 years of experience

Personal Information

Location: Stavropol, Russia (willing to relocate)

Phone: +7 916 611-32-58 E-mail: me@v1x.info Skype: focusshifter

Summary

A proficient software developer with substantial experience in building reliable, maintainable and scalable web applications and APIs.

Technologies

Ruby (MRI, JRuby): Ruby on Rails, Mongoid, RSpec, RuboCop, Reek.

PHP: Symfony 2, Doctrine, Twig, PHPUnit. Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis.

Client-side web: HTML, CSS (SASS), JavaScript (jQuery, AngularJS).

OS and tools: Linux, Git, nginx, Apache, Docker, Rancher, Prometheus, Teamcity.

Professional experience

Lead Developer and Co-Founder – Altread (https://www.altread.com)

August 2015 – February 2017

Ruby on Rails (running on JRuby), MongoDB, Docker, Rancher, Prometheus

- Created a sophisticated money distribution system from the ground up.
- Built an in-house billing and integrated it with Paymentwall.
- Set up CI and quick deployment solution with Docker, Teamcity and Rancher.

IT Consultant - 3waytalk (https://3waytalk.com)

June 2015 – May 2016

PHP, Symfony 2, Doctrine 2, MySQL (MariaDB), Redis, Freeswitch, Node.js

- Analyzed and provided reports of the state of the project, exposing potential problems and vulnerabilities, and advised on the fixes.
- Managed to substantially improve the fault tolerance and redundancy of the API and voice subsystems.
- Evaluated and set up the monitoring and CI infrastructure tooling.
- Integrated the external voice service provider (Twilio).

Programmer - Mail.Ru Group (http://corp.mail.ru/en)

July 2012 – June 2015

PHP, Symfony 2, Doctrine 2, MySQL (Percona), mogilefs, Gearman, JavaScript (AngularJS)

- Developed the backend for the BrightCam photo editing app (http://bcam.mobi).
- Provided a well-documented API for the iOS and Android developers to use.

- Built a reliable photo storage using mogilefs.
- Implemented the AppStore and Google Play in-app payments.

Lead Developer – Pokupanda LLC (PHP, Symfony, Doctrine, MySQL, Nginx) November 2010 – March 2012

- Was responsible for the whole development process of the new version of the service.
- Successfully launched the project with a small team in less than 3 months.
- Integrated 5 major russian payment systems.

Independent Web-developer (PHP, Codelgniter, Kohana, Python, Django, MySQL, JavaScript) August 2008 – October 2010

- Developed the content submission subsystem for the huge network of the hi-tech related websites (20+ sites).
- Created websites for the viral campaigns of RuPort Advertising Agency.

Art-director – Mystericon Studio

January 2008 - July 2008

Web-developer – Mystericon Studio (PHP, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript) July 2007 – January 2008

Independent Web-developer (PHP, MySQL, JavaScript) 2004 – July 2007

Education

North Caucasus State Technical University (2003 – 2008)

Specialist degree in IT (Engineer's degree in IT).

Graduated with honors. Average mark 5.0 (of 5.0).